Critical thinking exercise. I'm going to show you this first video. Then following that
will be a video about the three-fifths compromise. In the comments, I would love for you to tell me
what you glean in commonalities and differences between these two videos.
And if they give you any cause for concern. Under this map, white Texans receive one member
of Congress for every 445,000 residents. If you are Hispanic, it takes about 1.4 million
residents for that same representation. If you are black, it takes 2 million. In this proposal,
a Hispanic Texan has one-third the political value of a white Texan under this plan, and
a black Texan, one-fifth. It would take three Hispanics to equal the representation of one
white Texan and five black Texans to equal the value of one white Texan.
Any fair reading of this map shows what it actually does. It systematically dilutes Latino and black
voting strength while cementing and increasing Anglo control. We have not seen a map this
deliberately engineered by skin color since the days that brought Americans to march from
Selma to Montgomery, Alabama in the 1960s. Marches that helped to bring about the Voting Rights
Act just months later. You cannot say you found a way for one racial group that is 40% of our
state's population to have 70% political control in this state and say that the racial disparities
are merely coincidental. This map is an abomination. It is shameful.
So you're suggesting that it was okay for slaves' bodies to not only be used for labor, but also
used to empower those who are harming them to be fairly represented in government?
I think it's absolutely—they should have been used, period.
Okay, so then we agree on that. Yeah. So we agree on that. It was absolutely abhorrent. There's no
excuse for it. There's no justification for it. So then where's the argument? Because ultimately,
when there was an opportunity in Reconstruction for there to be equality and humans considered
in a real way and protected— Democrats torched it. Andrew Johnson. Yes, as well as the Supreme Court.
That's actually more important what we have to acknowledge. Please leave your critically
thought thoughts in the comments.
So let me see you next time.